A Register to the Natalie Grant Wraga Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1960-2002
  - "Polite Attitude Now Fad with Governments at War," Recorder, Menlo Park, California, 1965 February 10 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - "Intellectual Freedom - But...," San Carlos Enquirer, San Carlos, California, 1965 March 10 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - "The Chinese Communist Party in the International Communist Movement: Reflection on Chinese Isolation," Monograph Series No. 17, Research Institute on the Sino-Soviet Bloc, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - "Critique of the Communist Party's New Program," The Intercollegiate Review: A Journal of Scholarship and Opinion, Vol. 3, No. 2, 1966 November-December (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - "Window on Russia,", 1966
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 11: 14-22)
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
    - Typescripts
      - Volume 1-2, undated (Box-folder 12: 4)
        Photocopy
      - Volume 1-2, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 5-6)
      - Volume 1, 2001 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - Volume 2, 2001 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1967-2002 (Box-folder 13: 3-4)
  - "The 'Zinoviev Letter' Case," Soviet Studies, University of Glasgow, Vol. XIX, No. 2, October 1967 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    Printed copy. Includes review, Novoe Russkoe Slovo, 1968 February 15
  - "Political Forgeries: A Tool in Soviet Foreign Policy," paper presented before the Far Western Slavic Conference, Stanford University, California, 1969 April 26 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - "Forgery in International Affairs," Foreign Service Journal, 1970 May (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - "Peace as a Concept,", circa 1977 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    Typescripts
  - "The Potomack Furnace," draft, 1977 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    Typescript. Includes correspondence, 1977-1978
  - "Pis'mo v redaktsiiu" (Letter to the editor), Golos Zarubezh'ia, No. 8, Munich, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - "The Russian Section, A Window on the Soviet Union," Diplomatic History, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1978 Winter (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
    Drafts and printed copy
  - "The Russian Section, A Window on the Soviet Union," Diplomatic History, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1978 Winter (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - "Solidarity" (on Polish situation), 1982 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - "Political Disinformation: A Brief Outline,", 1985
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 14: 6-7)
    - Typescripts, 1985 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - "Forgotten Legends: Forgotten Brotherhood of Russian Truth,", 1986 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - "Deception on a Grand Scale," International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, Volume 1, No. 4, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Deception, a Tool of Soviet Foreign Policy, Nathan Hale Institute, Washington, D.C., 1987 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - "Operation Thunder," Conservative Review, Vol. 1, No. 2, 1990 April (Box-folder 14: 12)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "Masters of the Arctic," Conservative Review, Vol. 1, No. 5, 1990 August (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - "The New Way of Thinking," Conservative Review, 1991 Winter (Box-folder 14: 14-17)
    Typescript drafts and printed copy
  - "The Trust,", 1991
    - Background material (notes), undated (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 14: 19)
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Correspondence, International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, 1986 March – June (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Printed copy, American Intelligence Journal, 1991 Winter (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Miscellany, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - "A Simplistic Hypothesis – A New Game for Old Soviets," Conservative Review, Vol. 5, No. 3, 1994 May-June (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - "The Coup,", 1996 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - "The Gorbachev Foundation: A Tool in Moscow's Policies?" Conservative Review, Vol. 7, No. 4, 1996 July-August (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Murder in the Tiergarten: The Political Life of Vladimir Orlov, Intelligence Agent and Disinformer, Nathan Hale Institute, 1997
    - Drafts, undated (Box-folder 15: 8-11)
    - Draft, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Final draft, 1994 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Printed copy, 1997 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Review of the Issyk Kul Conference, 1997, Kyrgizia. (Box-folder 16: 3)
    Draft typescript
  - "Green Cross: Gorbachev and Global Enviro-Communism," The Register, Vol. IV, No. 3, 1998 Spring (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - "Environment in Politics,", 1997 November (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - "Is the Former Soviet Union up to its Old Tricks? Lessons from a Cold Warrior," Doublethink (Roundtable Discussion), circa 2001 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- Soviet Delegations File, 1957-1997 (Folder 25)
  Correspondence, schedules, pamphlets, reports, arranged chronologically by date of delegation
  - General, 1957-1991 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Russian women physicians, 1957 November 2-9 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Agricultural, 1958 August 1-31
    - Program and itinerary (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Memorandum (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Biochemists, 1958 November 12 - December 11
    - Program and itinerary (Box-folder 25: 5)
    - Memorandum (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Medical (endocrinologists), 1959 February 27 – March 28
    - Program, itinerary, lists of participants, and photos (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Notes (Box-folder 25: 8)
    - Memorandum (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Writers, 1960 February 17 – March 18
    - Program and itinerary (Box-folder 25: 10)
    - Travel documents (Box-folder 25: 11)
    - Committee on Leaders. Informal meeting (Box-folder 25: 12)
    - Notes (Box-folder 25: 13)
    - Memorandum and reports (Box-folder 25: 14)
  - Areas Closed to Travel by Soviet Citizens in Possession of Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Passports, 1961 (Box-folder 25: 15)
    Includes maps.
  - Soviet children's art exhibition, 1962 January – April
    - Program, Press Release (Box-folder 25: 16)
    - Photos, posters, brochures (Box-folder 25: 17)
  - Composers, 1962 October 6 – November 5 (Folder 26)
    - Programs and arrangements (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Travel documents (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Escort Interpreter Manual, U.S. Department Of State, July 1959 (Box-folder 26: 3)
      Printed copy.
    - Escort Interpreter Manual, U.S. Department Of State, July 1962
      Typescript.
  - Notes (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - State of the World Forum, San Francisco, 1997 November (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 26: 6)
- Writings by Others, 1908-1996
  Printed copies and typescripts, arranged alphabetically by name of author
  - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Unidentified, "Podmetnye pis'ma," Soiuz bor'by za osvobozhdenie narodov Rossii, 1957 January (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Unidentified, "Soviet Attitudes, Report #3: As Reported by Recent Visitors to the USSR," Information Center on Soviet Affairs, New York, 1962 April 15 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Unidentified, "Spies: Foot Soldiers in an Endless War," Time, October 11, 1971 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Ardamatskii, Vasilii, "Dve dorogi," Neva, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 26: 11-13)
  - Bakai, M. E., "Provokatory i provokatsiia," Byloe, #8, 1908 (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - Batiushin, Major General, "Tainaia voennaia razvedka i bor'ba s nei," Sofiia, 1939 (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - Blackstock, Paul W.
    - "Frauds and Forgeries of the Classic Cold War Period, 1947-1953, and After,", undated (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - "The Zinoviev Letter: An Intelligence Evaluation,", 1965 (Box-folder 26: 17)
      Typescript. Includes correspondence and reviews
  - Blackstock, Paul W.
    - "The Protocols of Zion" (chapter), circa 1965 (Box-folder 26: 18)
      Typescript. Includes letter to Prof. Stefan Possony, 1965 May 19
  - Butenko, Theodor. English translation of the booklet entitled "Enthüllungen über Moskau" (Disclosures about Moscow), published by Anti-Komintern, 1938 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Bradley, J. F. N., "The Russian Secret Service in the First World War," Soviet Studies, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Cherepnin, L. B., "Nekotorye problemy istoricheskogo istochnikovedeniia v trudakh V. I. Lenina," Istoricheskie zapiski, Moscow, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Delimars, E.
    - "La Tchéka a L'ouvre," Le Contract Social, 1966 March-April (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - "La Tchéka et Son 'Trust'," Le Contract Social, 1966 May-June (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Dobrokhotov, Leonid, Russia Today publications, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Doolin, Dennis, and Peter J. Golas, "On Contradiction in the Light of Mao Tse-Tung's Essay on 'Dialectical Materialism'," The China Quarterly, London, 1964 July-September (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Dukel'skii, S., "Cheka-GPU," Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo Ukrainy, 1928 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya, "Memoirs: 1921-1941," World Publishing Company, undated (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Fischer, Ben, "From Paris to Palo Alto,", undated (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Gatovskii, L., "Politika i voennaia strategiia," Gospolitizdat, 1943 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Gerson, Lennard D., "Felix Dzerzhinsky as Commissar of Transport and Chairman of the Supreme Council of the National Economy," paper presented at the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, Columbus, Ohio, 1978 October 14 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Golant, B., "Podlog – Tekhnologiia Proizvodstva," Zvezda, 1969 January (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - Haman, Arthur, "Friends and Family: Memoir Fragments" (source: Söbrad ja vaenlased, Tallin), 1967 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - Harris, William R., "Intelligence and National Security: A Bibliography with Selected Annotations," Center for International Affairs, Harvard University, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - Kasvinov, M., "Dvadtsat' tri stupeni vniz," Zvezda, #7-10, 1973 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Kolosov, L., and N. Petrov, "Immortality of Those Who Have Fallen," Joint Publications Research Service, 1972 March (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Komkov, G. D., "Sovetskie organy gosudarstvennoi bezopasnosti v gody Velikoi Otechestvennoi voiny," Moscow, Voprosy istorii, #5, 1965 May (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Konrad, N. I., "Sun'-Tszy. Traktat o voennom iskusstve – perevod i issledovanie," Moscow-Leningrad, 1950 (Box-folder 27: 20)
  - Koslov, Anton, "Metacorruption," afterward to Lev Timofeyev's book, Russia's Secret Rules, New York, 1992 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    Printed copy. Translated from Russian
  - Krenkel, Ernst, "Moi pozyvnye – Raem," Novyi mir, #9-11, 1971 (Box-folder 28: 2-4)
  - Leggett, George H., "Lenin's Reported Destruction of the Cheka Archives," Survey, Eastern Press Ltd., London and Reading, Vol. 24, No. 2 (107), 1979 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Martin, David, "Screening Federal Employees: A Neglected Security Priority," Heritage Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Mel'gunov, S. P.
    - "Dela i liudi Aleksandrovskogo vremeni," Berlin, 1923 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - "Vospominaniia i dnevniki," Paris, 1964 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Newman, Bernard, "The Sosnowski Affair," Werner Laurie, London, 1954 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Nikulin, Lev, "The Swell of the Sea," Moscow, 1966 (Box-folder 28: 10)
    Typescript. Translated from Russian
  - Oppenheimer, Andres, "Unmasking Marcos," (Chapter 12, Bordering on Chaos: Guerrillas, Stockbrokers, Politicians, and Mexico's Road to Prosperity), Boston, 1996 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Patek, Valerian (V. Slavich), "Ispoved Smenovekhovtsa," Sofia, 1924 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Possony, Stefan T., "Toward a Strategy of Supremacy," Praeger, New York, 1963 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Prianishnikov, Boris
    - "O revoliutsionnoi rabote Narodno-Trudovogo Soiuza rossiiskikh solidaristov," New York, 1957 (Box-folder 29: 4)
    - "Nezrimaia pautina" (The invisible web), New York, 1979 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      Typescript. Includes correspondence, 1970-1979
  - Rankovik, Aleksandar, "Za nekoi prashan'a na nashata emigratsiia," Skopje, Yugoslavia, 1961 July (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Rataev, L. A., "Note to N. P. Zuev," Byloe, #2, 1917 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Semennikova, Liubov, "Oktiabr' 1917-go...Chto zhe proizoshlo?" (October 1917...What really happened?), Svobodnaia mysl', #15, 1992 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Shearer, Lloyd, "The Japanese Spy Who Fingered Pearl Harbor," Parade, 1969 December 7 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Sidorov, B.
    - "Agenty smerti" (Death agents), Golos Zarubezh'ia, undated (Box-folder 29: 10)
      Printed copy. Includes one photograph
    - "Sovetskie legendy" (Soviet legends), Golos Zarubezh'ia, undated (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Smirnov, N. G., "Dnevnik shpiona," Moskovskii rabochii, Moscow-Leningrad, 1929 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Spence, Richard B., "The 'Savinkov Affair' Reconsidered," East European Quarterly, Vol. XXIV, No. 1, 1990 March (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Spendiarova, Tat'iana, "Podarok," published by Korev, S.E, Feodosia, 1922 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Subbotin, A., "Diplomatiia ili razboi: angliiskii shpionazh," Moskovskii rabochii, Moscow-Leningad, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Sukiennicki, W., remarks on "Le Conores de Fondation de L'International Communist,", 1963 July (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Sulc, Lawrence B.
    - Active Measures, Quiet War: And Two Socialist Revolutions, Nathan Hale Institute, Washington, D.C., circa 1985 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - "Security and the Soviet Émigré Problem: Hoods and Spies in 'The Big Candy Store'," Conservative Review, 1990 October (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Tang, Peter S. H.
    - "Maoism, Theory and Practice of Struggle against Modern Revisionism,", undated (Box-folder 30: 8)
    - "The Commune System in Mainland China," Pamphlet series No. 2, Research Institute on the Sino-Soviet Bloc, Washington, D.C., 1961 (Box-folder 30: 9)
    - "Moscow and Peking: The Question of War and Peace," Orbis, Vol. 5, No. 1, 1961 Spring (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - Thom, Françoise, "Perestroika and Glasnost: Dangers and Opportunities,", circa 1989 (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Tiltman, H. Hassell, "The Terror in Europe" (chapter IX, Plot and Counterplot), Frederick A. Stokes Company, New York, 1932 (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Tsevlovskii, M. A., "Sekretnye sotrudniki Moskovskoi okhranki 1880-kh godov," Golos minuvshego, #7-8, 1917 July-August (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Ulam, Adam, "Titoism," conference at the Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1964 October (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Valentinov, N., "Rozhdenie NEP, poiavlenie oppozitsii, bolezn' i smert' Lenina" (memoirs), undated (Box-folder 30: 15-16)
  - Vasiliev, A., "V chas dnia, vashe prevoskhoditel'stvo..." Moskva, #8, 1967 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Whitwell, John, "British Agent," William Kimber, London, undated (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A.
    - "The Legend of 'Maoism'," The China Quarterly, London, 1960 January-March (Box-folder 31: 3)
    - "A Stronger Oriental Despotism," The China Quarterly, London, 1960 January-March (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A.
    - "The Marxist View of Russian Society and Revolution," World Politics, Vol. XII, No. 4, 1960 July (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Wolfe, Bertram D.
    - "Lenin, the Architect of Twentieth-Century Totalitarianism,", undated (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - "Prelude,", 1940 (Box-folder 31: 7)
      Printed copy. Inscription reads, "From the Prelude of my only novel 'Deathless days'"
    - "The Russian Intelligentsia," The Antioch Review, 1946 Winter (Box-folder 31: 8)
    - "The Conversion of a Communism," The New Leader, 1954 June 7 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Zaslavskii, D. O., "Rytsar' chernoi sotni V. V. Shul'gin," Tsarskaia Rossiia, Leningrad, 1925 (Box-folder 31: 10)
    Printed matter
  - Zawodny, J. K., "Katyn Forest Massacre: Morals in American Foreign Policy," The Minnesota Review, 1963 Winter (Box-folder 31: 11)
- Newspapers and Clippings, 1917-1991
  Newspaper issues and clippings, arranged in two groups, general and Russkie vedomosti
  - General, 1956-1991 (Box-folder 31: 12-14)
- Photographs and Negatives, undated
  Arranged in two groups, prints and negatives
  - Photographic prints, unidentified, undated (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Negatives, unidentified, undated (Box-folder 31: 16)
- Oversize Materials, 1926-1965 (Folder 32)
  Scrapbook containing printed matter
  - Russkie vedomosti (newspaper), 1917 April-September (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1926-1965
    Contains printed matter
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1919-1937
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1919-1937 (Reading room workstation)